#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/neeraj-ravindra-b0107b15b (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Software as a Service (SaaS)
Enterprise Software
Android Development

# Neeraj Ravindra

Product@Samsung | IIM Bangalore PGP'22 | SJCE, Mysore '17 Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

## Summary

Quality-driven Product Manager with a flair for analytics and machine learning. Skilled in different aspects of product management such as market research, defining roadmaps, requirement refinement and prioritization along with excellent technical knowledge and presentation skills. Holds an MBA degree from IIM Bangalore

## Experience

Samsung Ads
Product Manager
July 2024 - Present (1 year 4 months)
Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

### Optum

Senior Product Analyst May 2022 - July 2024 (2 years 3 months) Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- Synthesized requirements for the 'Member Enablement' solution, projecting an annual revenue growth of ~USD 4M.
- Developed and integrated a feature for collecting SDoH data and health plan benefits, enhancing data access through APIs and decreasing latency by ~25%.
- Formulated the product vision for the Analytics solution by analyzing 10+ competitors and capturing the voice of the customer through 30+ stakeholder interactions
- Directed the development of an MVP through strategic planning, stakeholder management and analytical insights

#### Optum

Product Management Intern April 2021 - June 2021 (3 months) Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- Identified 7+ pain points in user journey and recommended solutions, estimated ~20% improvement in customer ratings
- Formulated go-to-market strategy, advocated build-buy combination, projected revenue ~USD 40Mn
- Received pre-placement offer, strategic insights in the payer market appreciated by top leadership

#### Avaya

Software Engineer July 2017 - July 2020 (3 years 1 month)

Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Streamlined authorization interfaces and developed a configuration service
   API adopted by 16+ development teams.
- Resolved customer issues, saving ~USD 3M+ and received 5-star satisfaction rating.
- Facilitated DevOps pipeline development for a new project, minimizing 2000 hours/month by integrating build & test tools for automated deployment

## Education

Indian Institute of Management Bangalore

Master of Business Administration - MBA · (August 2020 - April 2022)

Sri Jayachamarajendra College Of Engineering
Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Electronics and Communications
Engineering · (August 2013 - May 2017)